Financial Management and Budget, Office of; Records ua360
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Office of Financial Management and Budget Records
1938-1991
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
State University of New York at Albany. Office of Financial Management and Budget
ua360
7.2 cubic ft.
Includes annual preliminary and final budget requests of the University at Albany and its predecessor institutions, detailing operating costs and salaries. Formerly the Office of the Budget.
Box 14
Box 15
Access
Access to this collection is restricted because it is unprocessed. Portions of the collection may contain recent administrative records and/or personally identifiable information. Please contact an archivist for more information.
Acquisition Information
All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Historical Note
The Office of Financial Management and Budget is a unit within the Division of Finance and Administration that is responsible for management, planning, and analysis of the budget of the University at Albany. The University website describes the purpose of the Office as “to provide support to campus management for all levels of the organization in development, implementation, analysis, and monitoring of the campus operating budget.” It was previously called the Budget Office, and was overseen by the Vice President for Finance and Business. The department is key in developing budget requests to the State University of New York Administration for the coming year.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of preliminary and final budget requests for the University at Albany. These detail all minutia of the University budget including faculty and staff salaries, costs of campus activities and organizations. The sections dedicated to each department includes the duties performed by many faculty and staff including professors, librarians, and maintenance staff. Besides detailing staff salaries and costs, the report also includes material costs like supplies for the physical plant and acquisition costs for the library. There is also information on financial aid approved for students. All of this is included in yearly reports bound together and sent to the SUNY administration to be approved.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged in chronological order with two boxes containing surplus reports from the 1970s and 1980s.
Budget; Budget process; Reconciliation (Budget process); Administrative records; Financial Records; Budgets; UAlbany Finance & Business; State University of New York at Albany
- Legislative Budget, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Legislative Budget, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Legislative Budget, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Legislative Budget, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Legislative Budget, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Legislative Budget, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Legislative Budget, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Legislative Budget, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Legislative Budget, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Legislative Budget, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Legislative Budget, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Budget Summary, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Legislative Budget, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Budget Summary(incomplete), 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Legislative Budget, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Budget Request, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Budget Request, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Operational Budget Requirements, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Budget Request, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Operational Budget Requirements, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Budget Request, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Operational Budget Requirements, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Budget Request, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Budget Request, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Budget Request, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Preliminary Budget, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Budget Request, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Budget Request, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Budget Request, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Preliminary Budget Request, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Final Budget Request, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Final Budget Request, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Final Budget Request Supplement, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Final Budget Request, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Preliminary Budget Request, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Preliminary Budget Request, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Final Budget Request, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Final Budget Request, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Preliminary Budget Request, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Final Budget Request (pp 103-230), 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Final Budget Request ( pp 1-102), 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Preliminary Budget Request, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Final Budget Request, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Preliminary Budget Request President's Message, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Preliminary Budget Request, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Final Budget Request (pp 1-102), 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Final Budget Request (pp 103-251), 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Preliminary Budget Request, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Final Budget Request, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Preliminary Budget Request, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Final Budget Request, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Preliminary Budget Request, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Final Budget Request (pp 1-120), 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Final Budget Request (pp 121-240), 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Preliminary Budget Request, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Final Budget Request, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Preliminary Budget Request, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Final Budget Request, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Preliminary Budget Request, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Final Budget Request, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Preliminary Budget Request, 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Final Budget Request, 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Preliminary Budget Request Program Narrative, 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Preliminary Budget Request Statistical Data, 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Final Budget Request Program Narrative, 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Final Budget Request Statistical Data, 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Preliminary Budget Request Statistical Data, 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Preliminary Budget Request Program Narrative, 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Final Budget Request Program Narrative, 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Final Budget Request Statistical Data, 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Preliminary Budget Request Program Narrative, 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Preliminary Budget Request Statistical Data, 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Final Budget Request Program Narrative, 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Final Budget Request Statistical Data, 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Preliminary Budget Request Statistical Data, 1986-1987 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Preliminary Budget Request Program Narrative, 1986-1987 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Final Budget Request Program Narrative, 1986-1987 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Final Budget Request Statistical Data, 1986-1987 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Final Budget Request Program Narrative, 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Final Budget Request Statistical Data, 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Preliminary Budget Request Statistical Data, 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Preliminary Budget Request Program Narrative, 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Final Budget Request Statistical Data, 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Preliminary Budget Request Program Narrative, 1988-1989 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Preliminary Budget Request Statistical Data, 1988-1989 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Final Budget Request Program Narrative, 1988-1989 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Final Budget Request Statistical Data, 1988-1989 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Final Budget Request Program Narrative, 1989-1990 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Final Budget Request Statistical Data, 1989-1990 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Final Budget Request Narrative, 1990-1991 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Final Budget Request: Program Narrative, 1990-1991 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Final Budget Request: Statistical Data, 1990-1991 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Preliminary Budget Development, 1990-1991 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Final Budget Request: Program Narrative, 1991-1992 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Final Budget Request: Statistical Data, 1991-1992 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Budget Request (Final Narrative), 1992-1993 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Final Budget Request(Statistical Data), 1992-1993 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Final Budget Request, 1993-1994 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Final Budget Request, 1994-1995 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Final Budget Request (Statistical Data), 1995-1996 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Budget Request(Final Narrative), 1995-1996 (Box 13, Folder 12)